Now there's a few other things that you don't want to use email for no matter how badly you want to do it.
One, never ever deliver tragic email.
It's very, very impersonal.
You don't want to fire somebody, you don't want to let them know one of their co-workers died.
It totally makes it impersonal.
It shows disrespect for human being's feelings.
So you want to avoid that.
You also never want to discipline an employee or another person via email.
Why?
Again, it makes it very impersonal.
But, an email is totally different kind of communication, all we have to determine tone, feeling, thoughts, all of that are words.
So, if you write to me, I am so angry because you did that, well, I can't hear your tone of voice to determine how angry.
I can't see your facial expression to determine what your face is doing, what your body is doing.
So a person could take it in way too many different ways.
They could blow it off or they could get into hysterics when they're really not in trouble at all.
And it's kind of a co-bout, it's something that people who really like to avoid confrontation, really love disciplining via email.
So you don't want to do that.
Also in this, tie together a little bit, you never want to write emails when you're angry.
Because when you're angry, you know, in the present state, your thoughts you're angry, your body says you're angry, your voice says you're angry.
So you're going to sit down and you're going to fire off an email that will come across very, very hostile.
Always cool down before you send an email when you're angry.
Because you got to remember, once you hit that send button, it cannot be retrieve, it cannot be retread.
So whatever you say on those fits of anger, it's there, it's gone.
The damage has been done.